# **Javier Guzman**

San Francisco, California, United States z javguzman20@gmail.com d 415-994-8054 thtps://www.linkedin.com/in/javguzman/ https://javguzman.com/

## **SUMMARY**

Most recently the lead UX designer for Love Smiles with experience in project management, cross-team communication, B2B communication, various design tools, user research, and non-profit work. Proven ability to design new user experiences that drive customer engagement and loyalty as well as designing and improving experiences within per-existing design frameworks.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **UX Designer**

Love Smiles

June 2021 - September 2023, Chicago, IL

- · Collaborated with board members and outside business partners to create a coherent mobile and web experience which fulfilled their needs as well as those of everyday users.
- $\cdot \ \text{Created a design system for Love Smiles alongside accompanying usage guidelines}.$
- · Performed A/B testing for the website, increasing overall conversions by an average of 15%, leading to increased donations and community support.
- · Conducted extensive research on user behavior and preferences, implementing findings into task flows to create a website and mobile experience for various user groups.
- $\cdot$  Designed and executed wireframes and created the information architecture for the Love Smiles website, which were used to further build the website and mobile experience.
- Further revamped various portions of the Love Smiles website UX/UI and SEO, resulting in a 68% increase in user sessions, a 78% increase in unique visitors, a 19% decrease in bounce rate, a 21% increase in store conversions, and a 320% increase in traffic from non-direct sources.

#### Office Assistance

**Pioneer Contractors Inc.** 

January 2018 - March 2020, San Francisco, CA

- · Coordinated office supply orders for various teams, resulting in a streamlined process and cost savings over time.
- · Implemented a scheduling system for specific teams that increased productivity and on-time project completion.
- · Oversaw maintenance and upkeep of equipment, resulting in a decrease of downtime by and an increase in overall efficiency.

#### Marketing & Event Manager

Santa Cruz FGC

December 2014 - August 2016, Santa Cruz, CA

- Managed and organized medium to large scale in person gaming events which ranged from 40 to 100+ attendees on a weekly basis, tasks included pre-event team discussions, location prep-work and setup, and in-person managing of crowds and schedules.
- · Led the creation of advertising campaigns which resulted in a 100% increase in attendance, resulting in higher revenue and event space expansion to accommodate the increased turnout.
- Established partnerships with local businesses to act as prize-support sponsors in exchange for advertising campaigns through our social media platforms and live event broadcasts.
- · Created visuals for social media accounts, event banners, posters, stream overlays, and sponsor partnerships.

## **PROJECTS**

#### Alignimals: Zoo Building Puzzle-Game

Personal Endeavor • May 2023 - Present

- · Performed user research including card sorts, interviews, and tree tests to design the information architecture of the mobile app.
- · Created personas, affinity diagrams, user flows, wireframes, lo-fi prototypes, and mid-fi prototypes.
- $\cdot$  Curated and designed a cohesive, the matic design system for the game.

# **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelors of Science in Cognitive Science**

University of California – Santa Cruz + Santa Cruz, CA + Invalid date

# Masters of Science in Human-Computer Interaction

DePaul University · Chicago, IL · 2022 · 3.97

## **SKILLS**

Information Architecture, Prototyping, Wireframing, Mobile App Development, Responsive Web Design, Inclusive Design, Personas, Journey Maps, A /B Testing, Surveys, Card Sorting, User Interviews, First-Click Tests, Heatmaps, Task Analysis, Remote User Testing, Contextual Inquiries, Python, HTML, CSS, Photoshop, Figma, Adobe XD, Native Spanish Speaker, Native English Speaker